MD NURUL AFSER SIDDIQUE

IT Security Specialist

Dhaka, Bangladesh afsersid@gmail.com +8801841344635

Experienced Information Technology Professional with a demonstrated history of working in the banking and IT Services industry. Skilled in Windows and Linux Server, IT Security, LogRhythm SIEM, VAPT, ISO: ISMS Audit, Active Directory, Exchange, SCCM etc.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Executive Officer

IT Security Specialist

National Bank Limited - Dhaka, Bangladesh

June 2015 to Present

- Monitor, develop, assess and carry out IT security policies, processes, and measures to protect the sensitive data of NBL computers and server infrastructure and maintain high-security standards.
- Ensure the operational and technical documentation related to Information security and its domains.
- Perform internal security audits against policy, processes, departments, systems, networks, and applications.
- Perform Vulnerability Assessment & Penetration Test among sensitive IT systems, platforms, and processes.
- ****Summary-SIEM, VAPT, IT AUDIT, ISO 27001, IT SECURITY****

Officer

IT Specialist (Network & System)

Dutch-Bangla Bank Limited – Dhaka, Bangladesh January 2013 to May 2015

- Planning, operation, security, and day to day management of the organization's IT infrastructure including servers, network-connected devices, and all data communications, operating systems: Windows, Linux etc.
- Assist in the selection, testing, deployment, customization and post implementation troubleshooting of new IT systems (network devices, servers etc.).
- Analyze the effectiveness of computer systems and develop strategies to improve IT productivity.
- Maximizing network performance by monitoring network devices, troubleshooting network problems and outages, scheduling and performing upgrades and enhancements.
- Monitoring network security in assigned areas of network administration responsibility and working with senior colleagues to resolve security issues.



EDUCATION

Master of Engineering in Advanced Engineering Management

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) - Dhaka 2015 to 2018

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

Military Institute of Science and Technology (MIST), BUP - Dhaka 2004 to 2008

Higher Secondary in Science

BAF Shaheen College - Dhaka 2001 to 2003



SKILLS

- MS EXCHANGE
- LINUX
- ACTIVE DIRECTORY, SCCM
- IT AUDIT
- ISMS (ISO 27002)
- SIEM (LOGRHYTHM)
- VAPT
- WINDOWS
- Information Security
- Network Security
- Cyber Security
- Python, Java, HTML, Github
- Android App Development



LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/afsersid

https://afsersid.github.io/



CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES -----

Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)

RHCSA

MCSA

Accredited Technical Professional- HP BladeSystem Solutions Support V8 Accredited Platform Specialist- HP Proliant Servers



ADDITIONAL INFORMATION -----

Logrhythm- Security Information and Event Management (SIEM)
VAPT (Nessus, Nexpose, Metasploit, nmap, wireshark, OpenVAS, OWASP ZAP)

Course Completion:

Security+ (Udemy)
Google- IT Security Course (Coursera)
IBM- Python for data Science (edX)